[Music]
USGS said the flow heading down to the
ocean is traveling about 17 miles an
hour it's now entering the water at two
points the flow has also grown by about
28 acres since yesterday
[Music]
and the DNR has cited six more people
for loitering or refusing to leave the
evacuation zone in lower Puna bringing
the total of citations to nearly 50
since early May those fines can range up
to five thousand dollars
[Music]
I'm from the corner side the west side
of the island right now that sides
getting a big hit with the vog and my
family's over there my kids over there
my wife is over there and you know I I'm
here working so it feels good to to
provide the support and to also think of
everything this whole island because
it's affecting this whole island what we
do is we drive around the community
basically supporting HPD and observing
any type of unsafe acts or anything like
that we also drive around to kind of
show the citizens residents that we're
here and in support of them it's
important that they know that we're here
so that way they don't feel alone they
see us driving around and they see
soldiers driving around and they see
well you know they don't really get that
over here this is a small isolated area
so when you see that I believe in their
heads you know they're not forgotten or
dismissed or anything like that another
reason we're out here is to deter an
acts of crime acts of hey looting you
know a lot of people evacuees that left
their homes they left it you know they
left everything everything is there and
a lot of people that think all that
stuff for grabs it's not so we got a
kind of show that that's what we're here
for - it's very meaningful um because
you know we this is something that we as
Guardsmen this is our priority mission
to take care of our home I guess no
words can really describe that
[Music]
you