hola welcome to butterfly Spanish me
llamo Ana and in today's lesson we're
going to learn tons of vocabulary mucho
vocabulary Oh
mucho mucho vocabulario muchas palabras
many words yes and these words if you
are an English native speaker you
already know these words but if you're
learning Spanish and you're an English
native speaker it will be very easy muy
facil para T aprender learn estas
palabras these words because these words
are almost identical between English and
Spanish either because they have the
same origin because it was a borrowing
that one language took from the other
and they just became embedded in each
language pronunciation might be
different maybe spelling my might be
different only because in Spanish we use
many accent marks muchos Santos and in
English well there are not accent marks
I'm going to go through the list of
these words that would help you improve
your vocabulary in a few minutes and
have more words which are like your best
gun to conquer a language vocabulary
with vocabulary you win the war yes you
do so we're going to start you're going
to notice possible bass a bear bass note
ah okay noise creepy las palabras and
English I didn't write the words in
English and not because I am lazy well
sometimes I am more flow ha more flow ha
more lazy
I didn't do it because they are to say
and so I don't want you to to say it in
English I want you to see oh that's the
same word it's just pronounced
differently so learn the Spanish words
without much blah blah blah that I
usually like as you probably know if you
were one of my subscribers vamos a
empezar sin tanto bla bla bla sin tanto
and the first world is actually number
one not because in my last like as you
will see is not alphabetic alphab in
alphabetical order and ordained
alphabetical it's just an order of my
brain processed the first word la
primera palabra la primera palabras me
favorita el coyote and coyote because it
has a very nice history and this word
actually comes from Nahuatl now what'll
that war comes with coyotl
quartel like now what we'll call yo -
and that has that evolved as karate in
english the pronunciation is different
you to do know that but is elko yo t
l calmly l cobble a circular circular
now you notice here I push here L the
article and here I didn't I did it
because this is and now this is a thing
an object and this is an adjective
this is a characteristic of something
many of the table Lamas is circular Oh
last gentes the tires like gentes on
circular so that's why it doesn't come
with an article it comes by itself
because it's a characteristic ax the
algo of something the algo el calor well
I think in English the spelling might be
different depending on its England or
North America but el calor
you can tell el calor el full neural el
funner al
poom la explosion con home bonito acento
bonito ascent Allah o la X plus y on LOL
el hotel without the sound of the as
share porque la is muda mute in Spanish
and espanol el hotel maybe you don't
like the hotel you like to go with your
car and park it right there then you go
to AA l Motel a motel yes
if you go on a road trip in Mexico which
I wouldn't recommend right now for some
part in like Chile you may say el motel
ello 10 Don gonna grow up in Mexico
right now por favor no el perform a
helper for me I'll perform a and now I
went on my
favourite songs from a band from Cuba
it's a bear for me they guardin yes it's
like the perfume of the gardenias those
white beautiful flowers that smell so
delicious perform al perform a la
cancion se llaman performing a gardenias
there's another song that is called
those gardenias parity - gardenias -
flowers for you he'll perform a natural
natural Oh me me gusta la comida ah -
right
I like natural food mmm hasta la comida
natural que no tengo muchas Kimiko's
without chemicals not to die there
really
Oh getting really there's really
something bad that happened terribly my
R is not very good as you probably know
huh
but it's it's like French I have some
French in my blood I guess maybe you -
oh really oh really oh really
Oh sobbing really when you don't like
something that you reading you can say
sobbing or really sub it or gravely you
don't like it
act or act door knock door
like for example remember the movie Troy
when Brad Pitt calls that guy ah Hector
Hector K actor I mean to make that like
five times story probably like his
throat probably was killed already like
that oh maybe they get he got a double
and he didn't even open his mouth that
Brad Pitt spoiled actor Brad Pitt
actor/director Tarantino a soon director
muy bien bravo Bravo
muy bien Aurore air or yes roar
Tarantino know as soon director a soon
act or no no estas mal you're wrong it's
that smile as soon be wrecked or Oh
bueno entiendo or entiendo our entiendo
now I understand saliba you see when you
probably see when I get too excited when
I'm explaining Spanish up in my saliva
Sally oh come on you a como Euboea like
rain like romantic rain Saliba saliva
normal normal normal
hey al with something is away uh-oh
Callie noise et al todo lo que tú
quieres either I'll I'll check it and
check it although it is a little bit
outdated no to show these like no e
transfers and all that stuff
ah and chickens are still useful my
landlady asked me for checks all the
time check and check your loss check is
in plural el piano I do quiero aprender
a tocar piano I want to learn to play
piano
jo quiero aprender a tocar piano elBulli
tambien also I want to learn to play the
violin quiero aprender a tocar el bialy
medio Cree
well that's not a very nice word now so
na palabra Bonita no no no es una
palabra negativa me do Cray lb ruse lb
ruse
Oh L&T beerus no cuando cuando tienes UN
beerus and to computadora when you have
a virus in your computer own beerus and
to computadora or the contact yeah stay
you like someone gave me a virus like
you have a beerus and salmon yes it is
in 700s and washes oh my mom's illness
la diabetics and I think many Mexicans
suffer from that it's like one of the
number one illness in mexico something
like that
i Wasi algo por el estilo something like
that is algo por el estilo la diabetes
diabetes now that all those candidates
for the US are like going on debate and
debate all the time I'm sick of them
already but I like to watch them armed
so so like oh oh frustrated watching
that el de batty mm-hmm vas a ver el
próximo about are you going to watch
next EP maybe yes maybe no tal vez see
tal vez no Salva see talvez no seguimos
artificial artificial lo que no es
natural is artificial
where is not natural is artificial
asexual as sex well oh my my English ah
ah sexual
ah sexual la capitale la capitale
vertical vertical Universal Universal
formal when I go to work I dress up for
my
maybe Stowe de manera formal see
informal on the weekend el fin de semana
may bestow de manera informal de manera
casual informal s casual informal almost
sexual almost sexual and you do not
pronounce the H s almost sexual muy bien
el general el general en el ejército
mean the Army is the general but without
the articles seen without al articulo
the article you say can write sometimes
when I speak I say well and general a
stone also said this doesn't happen but
Henry and Henry particular particular
matter yeah oh is material came at the
reallys st k material assess a what is
this material came material is st o is
the plastic oh s plastic oh you can say
what is like wine material is made of
the k material esta h o the chemical
starch
all right no I miss classes on or Alice
because I don't give you science or
alley when you are speaking in public
use it on this course or I'll know I
script or add some politicians
eyewitness politic OHS have their speech
written and they try to like look just
like just to skim it but some
politicians
oh my sister says that Obama never has a
speech that he's always talking hurry
folks see see folks here we're talking
about and he doesn't read the speech hey
let's move all right
Obama is me all right original nah well
maybe when he maybe because he is very
very original he doesn't write his Peter
he's a speech man or woman doesn't write
his speech because we are he not he
likes to make up stuff he goes original
personnel for a champ low window
nobody etre bahar when I tell my bosses
Oh tengo problemas personae when I do
not go to work cuando no voy a trabajar
I tell my boss la vie bohème a heffa
tengo un problema persona have a
personal issue I cannot go to work I
personally show what like I do not sleep
till your dad that's not just jokes
don't believe I'm lazy I'm not no so if
you're hot no se lo ha blue that
singular singular not pure muchos ready
can Robbie Kyle come on Luz group or
Friedrich Alex and radical groups use
here a lot on the Spanish news group was
radical is radical groups you know
terrorists like all those people that
make radical decisions as you see on is
radical is radical 3 1201 for example in
the Day of the Dead in Mexico a semo's 3
to Alice a Samos entreat one for the
dead people so for instance I put
candles and they fooled my father liked
and the drinks my father liked
and some of those yellow flowers and
paso total because I'm making as Rick
1212 para mi padre porque mi padre
murió en me tradición and my tradition
we make every 12 every year so he common
needs for drink that stuff that's just
imagination but you know it's it's a
ritual it's something we have fun with
we like it in my family recline drew dad
I come from a rural place a small town
before I went to school I lived in a
rural person our Munna una zona
true dad right yeah I'd remember
sometimes I came out of my house and if
my neighbors cows were coming up I was
going to be late for school because he
had 150 cows and I had to wait until all
those cows passed the street so then I
can run to school so I had to go I have
to go now because the cows are going to
come by a quarter to a so I had to run
first before the cows enter the last
backup so that was our rural place Mugen
Groudon now I live in the city now I'm a
city girl I mean you live in a rural
place just tell me about it right in the
firm I would like to hear your story
sexual well sexual same word sexual in
fed sexual what am i speaking English oh
I'm sorry
sexual in failure in failure I don't
like that word because it's about you
know sorry in bed your super your Oh
super dear I forgot to put that word is
the same to super you're exactly the
same written same whining as in English
super you're in failure
I'm teaching in those words but I don't
like those like so pretty I think show
beats I'm a communist maybe in failure
II ASL total de las palabras total
cuándo es la cuenta when you ask for
the bill la cuenta por favor trial total
of why you consume lo que con su mr. el
total koalas el total muy bien
yes de sel total they meet classy I hope
you enjoyed this lesson
espero calles disfruta lo de esta clase
espero que esta tomando notice Scooby
endo aprendiendo estudiando espanol it
is a pleasure teaching you Spanish and I
hope you're learning a lot if you like
my channel City gusta me canal and
YouTube subscribe to my channel you can
also donate to my channel so I can keep
posting more lessons for you and if you
don't want to donate and you don't want
to subscribe then I guess just watch my
lessons they might be good for you
anyway I have to go now I never want to
go but now I have to go tengo que me
tengo que tengo hambre voy a comer
adios