I want to pick up her speech because I
think I can sell it for a lot of money
here Juanita
[Applause]
you're gonna see that tonight right
thank you very much Juanita you have
been fantastic in your kind words this
is truly an incredible organization
thanks also to the members of NFIB Board
of Directors who I've spent time with
just took some wonderful pictures with
good looking group I have to tell you
and Board Chairman Steve Schramm thank
you thank you Steve thank you together
you've been a powerful voice for
America's small businesses and now you
have a true friend and ally
in the White House you know I'm honored
to be with you today for really this
historic celebration this was something
when they asked me to do I didn't think
about it for more than about a second I
said I'll do it you are very special
people and let me officially say on
behalf of the American people happy 75th
anniversary to the National Federation
of Independent Business I tell you you
deserve a big happy
joining us today are some terrific
people who work very very hard and
actually they are starting to get a lot
of credit in fact we had our highest
poll numbers today can you believe this
so they're doing a good job
our highest you know the old story when
I was campaigning I only mentioned that
when we're doing well in the polls when
we're not doing well I don't talk about
it like all of you you do the same thing
secretary minuchin Steve thank you very
much doing a great job
secretary Acosta Alex and administrator
Linda McMahon Thank You Linda thank you
they are fighting hard for small
business and for large businesses
they're fighting hard for our country
frankly each and every day and they're
doing a terrific job most importantly I
want to thank all of you the small
business owners who are the engine of
American prosperity and I you know I've
been saying it for a long time but you
really are you look at even the stats so
you look at the numbers you look at the
taxes that are paid you look at the jobs
it's all about small business so small
businesses really I say this to Linda
McMahon all the time head of small
business but small business is really
big right Linda it's really big
for many years Washington tried to hold
you back and tear you down crushing the
Americans small business with crippling
taxes and oppressive regulation but all
that has changed starting in November
the Trump administration is with you and
we are with you 100% and always will be
[Applause]
instead of punishing entrepreneurship we
are now promoting entrepreneurship
especially that guy in the corner Main
Street is thriving in America is winning
once again you know we're respected
again this country is respected again
[Applause]
before going any further today I want to
take a moment to address something
you've been reading a lot about the
illegal immigration crisis on our
southern border it's been going on for
many many decades and many years and it
has its ups and it's downs and all we
need is good legislation and we can have
it taken care of we have to get the
Democrats to go ahead and work with us
because as a result of Democrat
supported loopholes and our federal laws
most illegal immigrant families and
minors from Central America who arrive
unlawfully at the border cannot be
detained together or removed together
only released these are crippling
loopholes that cause family separation
which we don't want as a result of these
loopholes roughly half a million illegal
immigrant family units and minors from
Central America have been released into
the United States since 2014 at
unbelievably great taxpayer expense
nobody knows how much we're paying for
this monstrosity that's been created
over the years legislation that nobody
has any idea what they're doing they
don't even know what it means and you
have to see this it's a mile high child
smugglers exploit the loopholes and they
gain illegal entry into the United
States
putting countless children in danger on
the perilous Trek to the United States
they come up through Mexico Mexico does
nothing for us you hear it here they do
nothing for us they could stop it they
have very very strong laws try staying
in Mexico for a couple of days see how
long that lasts okay
[Applause]
they do nothing for us and I see it
through NAFTA I see with a hundred
billion dollars plus that they make on
trade through NAFTA one of the worst
deals ever made by this country a
disaster and we're trying to equalize it
it's not easy but we're getting there
it's not easy and we're gonna take care
of our American farmers and we're going
to take care of our manufacturers and
our manufacturing jobs but they're
making unbelievable amounts of money and
that's not including the drugs that are
flowing through our border because we
have no wall and we have no protection
the drugs that are coming in from Mexico
and through the southern border is
disgraceful so we'll see whether or not
we can make a reasonable NAFTA deal or
deal doesn't have to be called NAFTA we
can do one on one with Mexico one on one
with Canada and by the way Canada they
like to talk there are great neighbor
they fought World War two with us we
appreciate it
they fought World War one with us and we
appreciate it but we're protecting each
other
there was a story two days ago in a
major newspaper talking about people
living in Canada coming into the United
States and smuggling things back into
Canada because the tariffs are so
massive the tariffs to get common items
back into Canada are so high that they
have to smuggle them in they buy shoes
than they wear them they scuff them up
they make them sound old or look old now
what she did horribly Dairy Dairy two
hundred and seventy five percent tariff
so basically that's a barrier without
saying it's a barrier and I told them if
they don't change their way so we have a
tremendous deficit people say well
there's really not that much of a
deficit well they're not including two
things energy and timber and those are
the two big things when it comes to
Canada
now we have to change our ways we can no
longer be this stupid country we want to
be the smartpak
[Applause]
so hopefully we'll be able to work it
out with Canada we're very good
relationships with Canada we have for a
long time and hopefully that'll work out
but Canada is not going to take
advantage of the United States any
longer and Mexico is not going to take
longer and when I campaigned I said I
will either renegotiate NAFTA or I'll
terminate it and we'll start from an
even base and people are afraid of that
you know I've had so many people they
come up they say oh please don't
terminate enough they said but it's no
good yeah but we know what we have it's
true people are worried because they
know what they have if you look at I
love the American farmer more than
anybody they have backed me I love the
American farmer
[Applause]
and by the way tell you a little while
because it's in one of my notes the
American farmer virtually will not have
to pay anymore state tax on their farms
when they pass away and they want to
leave it to their children and that goes
for almost all small businesses you
won't have the estate tax to pay anymore
which was crippling that was in our bill
[Applause]
see a young guy is standing up now he's
too young to be leaving it so that means
he's a beneficiary either don't act too
happy there's a wealthy father there
don't act too happy said your father oh
wow the answer is yes okay and you know
what you're both happy okay you're both
happy and I'm honored to have done it
because it was destroying the estate tax
small businesses and farms destroying
him people were more mortgaging them to
the hilt to pay the tax and then they
couldn't pay the interest on the
mortgage and the banks would take them
away you don't have to pay the estate
tax any longer in most cases in other
words loopholes you have your farms
really big you start to pay it's a
pretty big level you know that pretty
big that would have to be a pretty big
farm these loopholes have created a
massive child smuggling trade can you
believe this in this day and age we're
talking about child smuggling we're
talking about women smuggling in this
day and age the worst has been in
history because the Internet has led to
this you think back 200 500 a thousand
years ago the worst it's ever been women
smuggling child's murder since last year
child smugglers who are very very
sophisticated they've learned that the
loopholes in this horrible rotten system
that the Democrats have to help us fix
because we need the votes we could have
the Republican votes a hundred percent
we still don't have enough votes people
don't understand that we need Democrat
votes to get it fixed
these smugglers know these rules and
regulations better than the people that
drew them as a result there has been a
325 percent increase in minors and a
four hundred and thirty five percent
increase in the smuggling or attempted
smuggling of families and minors into
our country we're stopping them all the
time by the thousands but they still get
through we have no wall we have no
border security without a border you
don't have a country you have a country
under current law we have only two
policy options to respond to this
massive crisis we can either release all
illegal immigrant families and minors
who show up at the border from Central
America or we can arrest the adults for
the federal crime of illegal entry those
are the only two options totally open
borders or criminal prosecution for law
breaking and you want to be able to do
that we don't want people pouring into
our country we want them to come in
through the process through the legal
system and we want ultimately a
merit-based system where people come in
based on merit
[Applause]
keep in mind those who apply for asylum
legally at ports of entry are not
prosecuted the fake news media back
there doesn't talk about them they're
fake they are helping they are helping
these smugglers and these traffickers
like nobody would believe they know it
they know exactly what they're doing and
it should be stopped because what's
going on is very unfair to the people of
our country and they violate the law
people that come in violate the law they
endanger their children in the process
and frankly they endanger all of our
children you see what happens with ms-13
where your sons and daughters are
attacked violently kids that never even
heard of such a thing are being attacked
violently not with guns but with knives
because it's much more painful in
inconceivable here we are talking about
business inconceivable that we even have
to talk about ms-13 and other gangs they
attack violently the most painful way
possible and a bullet is too quick and
we're allowing these people into our
country not with me we're taking them
out by the thousands they're taking them
out by the thousands
[Applause]
so what I'm asking Congress to do is to
give us a third option which we have
been requesting since last year the
legal authority to detain and promptly
remove families together as a unit we
have to be able to do this this is the
only solution to the border crisis we
have to stop child smuggling this is the
way to do it and ultimately we have to
have a real border not judges thousands
and thousands of judges they want to
hire who are these people when we vet a
single federal judge it goes through a
big process everybody that's ever met
her or him they come they complain they
don't complain they say he's brilliant
she's brilliant he's not smart enough to
be a judge now we're hiring thousands
and thousands what country does this
judges I won't say I refuse to say it I
hope they picked that up back there they
won't know what seriously what country
does it they said sir would like to hire
about five or six thousand more judges
five or six thousand now can you imagine
the graft that must take place you're
all small business owners so I know you
can't imagine a thing like that would
happen but here's a guy they say could
you please be a judge come on get it
they line up to be a judge it's horrible
we don't want judges we want security on
the border we don't want people coming
in we want them to come in through a
legal process like everybody else that's
waiting to come in to our country
and it got so crazy that all of these
thousands we now have thousands of
judges border judges thousands and
thousands and by the way when we release
the people they never come back to the
judge anyway they're gone they're in
your system that's it if they're good
that's great and if they're bad you'll
have killings you'll have murders you'll
have this you have that you have crime
your crime
and remember these countries that we
give tremendous far and aid to in many
cases they send these people up and
they're not sending their finances that
sound familiar remember I made that
speech and I was badly criticized oh
what's so terrible what he said turned
out I was a hundred percent right that's
why I got elected
[Applause]
we want a great country we want a
country with heart but when people come
up they have to know they can't get in
otherwise it's never gonna stop
whether it was President Bush President
Obama President Clinton same policies
they can't get him changed because both
sides are always fighting this is maybe
a great chance to have a change but one
of them says we want to hire 5,000 more
judges
I don't want judges I want border
security I don't want to try people I
don't want people coming in do you know
if a person comes in and puts one foot
on our ground it's essentially welcome
to America welcome to our country you
never get them out because they take
their name they bring the name down they
file it then they let the person go they
say show back up to court in one year
from now one year but here's the thing
that in itself is ridiculous like 3%
come back the other thing they have is
they have professional lawyers some are
for good others are do gooders and
others are bad people and they tell
these people exactly what to say they
say say the following they write it in I
am being harmed in my country my country
is extremely dangerous I fear from my
life say that congratulations you'll
never be removed this is given to them
by lawyers who are waiting for them to
come up and they're not all bad people
there are practical people but in a way
that's cheating because they're given up
statements they're not coming up for
that reason they're coming up for many
other reasons and sometimes for that
reason there's been a 1,700 percent
increase in asylum claims over the last
10 years think of that think of that
we're a great country but you can't do
that smugglers know how the system works
they game the system they
Gaming it's so easy for them they're
smart they didn't go to the Wharton
School of Finance that it but you know
what they're really smart the United
States has just surpassed Germany as
having the most asylum seekers of any
nation on earth can you imagine that can
you imagine and Germany we talk about
Germany they allowed millions of people
in and by the way their crime from the
time they started is up more than 10%
and that's one of the reasons it's at
that level is because they don't like
reporting that kind of crime so they put
it down as different kind of crime but
their crime is up more than 10% since
they started taking them and I heard
somebody said that crooked Hillary
Clinton was questioning that statistic
she said it's not true it's not true
didn't she already have her chance I've
been I've
[Applause]
I'll tell you what when you read the IG
report with these really dishonest
people and I was never a deep state guy
let me tell you we got some bad people
that are doing bad things but when you
read that IG report about how she got
away with what she got away with it's a
disgrace it's a total disgrace
and you ought to see the hearings that
are right now on television but that
folks are being you know they're going
on to the mainstream fake news media
they want to focus on immigration
because they want to keep the cameras
away from the hearings because those
hearings are not good for them in fact
they're a disaster for them the whole
thing is a scam it's a scam and what's
happened is a disgrace so we have a
house that's getting ready to finalize
an immigration package that they're
going to brief me on later and that I'm
gonna make changes to we have one chance
to get it right we might as well get it
right or let's just keep it going but
let's do it right we have a chance we
want to solve this problem we want to
solve family separation I don't want
children take it away from parents and
when you prosecute the parents for
coming in illegally which should happen
you have to take the children away now
we don't have to prosecute them but then
we're not prosecuting them for coming in
illegally that's not good we want to end
the border crisis by finally giving us
the legal authorities and the resources
to detain and remove illegal immigrant
families altogether and bring them back
to their country we have to bring them
back to their country now think of all
that aid that we give some of these
countries hundreds of millions of
dollars we give to some of these
countries and they send them up well I'm
gonna go very shortly for authorization
that when countries abuse us by sending
their people up not their best we're not
going to give any more aid to those
countries why the hell should we why
should
so this is a responsible common-sense
approach that all lawmakers should
embrace Democrats and Republicans so
remember we need the Democrats people
say oh you have the majority well in the
Senate we have one but you need 60 so
we'll be it if we get a hundred percent
we'll be at fifty one hundred percent
will be at fifty one so we need nine
votes we need ten twelve thirteen votes
we have to have Democrat support because
we need to go not just a majority
unfortunately which we could get we need
to go to 60 60 out of a hundred
we need Democrat support they don't want
to give it because Democrats love open
borders let the whole world come in let
the whole world ms-13 gang members from
all over the place come on in we have
open borders and they view that possibly
intelligently except that it's
destroying our country they view that as
potential voters some day they get a
vote for Democrats because they can't
win on their policies which are horrible
they found that out in the last
presidential election
in fact their only policy was that
Donald Trump is a bad guy he's a bad
person vote against up and they said if
so many there's hundreds of millions of
dollars of negative ads nobody's ever
been hit like that I used to go home I
started disliking myself sure I said man
am i that bad the problem is they never
told anybody what they're doing they
didn't talk about tax cuts by the way
they want to take away you tax cuts and
they want to substantially increase your
taxes they didn't talk about crime all
they talked about was Trump so when
people got to the booth they said ah
we're gonna vote Democrat we're gonna
vote that but then they get up they said
but what does she stand for what are
they stand for
they just say Trump now I'm going with
Trump and that's what happened
we got tremendous Democrat support it's
a beautiful thing that was a beautiful
night do you agree I was a beautiful
I was some night hours sometime but you
have to stand for something and you have
to stand for safety and security of our
country we can't let people pour in
they've got to go through the process
and maybe it's politically correct or
maybe it's not we got to stop separation
of the families but politically correct
or not we have a country that needs
security that needs safety that has to
be protected so we're here today to talk
about small business and the incredible
progress we're making as a country we
really have made unbelievable progress
and we're making with the help and
support of our wonderful friends at the
NF IB and you've heard these numbers and
if I would have said these numbers
during the campaign the fake news would
have said this is the most ridiculous I
wouldn't have said these numbers I would
have said half who would have known
but things have kicked in better and as
an example you saw the poll that was
recently taken small business poll the
most optimistic in history in the
history of the poll
that's why I figured that probably this
would be a friendly crowd but nobody
would have believed these numbers if I
said I'm doing a big campaign we have
created more than 3.4 million new jobs
since election day 3.4 million think of
what that means and by the way we do
need people coming through the border we
do need people and again we want people
you know I have a lot of companies
moving in big companies you look at
Foxconn and Wisconsin they're coming in
many thousands and thousands of people
Chrysler is moving from Mexico back into
Michigan many car companies are coming
back into our country many companies are
coming back they're coming back from
where they went now they're coming back
because of all of the things we've done
with regulations with tax cutting but we
need people to take care we have the
lowest unemployment rate 3.8 percent we
need people so we want people to come in
but they have to be people that can help
us and can help these companies fulfill
what they want to fulfill
unemployment claims are at a 44 year low
that's a great dumper maybe the one that
makes me happiest is this because I
remember I'd go around I'd say what do
you have to lose vote for me the
Democrats have always been with you
vote for me they've you know bad
education the most unsafe parts of the
country all of these different I'd say
what you have to do what do you have to
do vote for me what do you have to lose
unemployment for african-americans is
that the lowest level in history it's
like what do you have to lose I would go
around and talk and some people would
say don't say that it's not nice I'd say
look it's true so badly treated and now
the lowest level of unemployment in
history for african-americans and for
Hispanic the lowest level of
unemployment in history and for women
the lowest level of unemployment in 21
years soon it will be history
just like I promised during the campaign
our economic policy can be summed up in
three very beautiful words words that
you probably know better than anybody in
this country jobs jobs jobs and I
shouldn't say this to the people in this
room because you'll end up not having
liked my speech but wages for working
people are finally after 22 years rising
again in our country I'm sorry to do
the only thing you can hold against me
but I think you're also very happy about
it actually I know you will according to
the NF I B's latest survey the share of
small businesses raising worker and
benefit pay has just set a new all-time
record so it's a new all-time record
we've broken many records I could go on
and on business optimism is the highest
that's ever been in our country
that means more hardworking Americans
are able to support their family
contribute to their community and live
the American Dream at the center of
America's researchers are the massive
tax cuts that Republicans passed and
that I signed into law six months ago
this week not one Democrat voted for the
tax cuts and they are suffering now
because they got to lose a lot of races
that they thought they were going to win
they wish they had that vote to do over
again we have numerous states for Senate
where I think they're going to be in big
trouble
it's the biggest tax cut and reform in
American history
[Applause]
and you know the story not since Ronald
Reagan have they done any major tax
cutting and they've wanted to many many
times I tell this story all the time I
said I don't understand it cutting taxes
should not be hard to sell right is
there anything easier we're going to cut
your taxes and you can't get it through
so the leadership came to my beautiful
Oval Office it is a beautiful office
great office and they talked about the
tax reform I said what's the word reform
what does that mean reform does that
mean you're gonna raise taxes what does
it mean
no sir we have the tax reform act of
2017 I said no I don't want to go reform
nobody knows what reforming then I look
back at all of the times they tried to
pass tax cuts they don't use the word
tax cuts they use the word tax reform
I said nobody knows what reform means
they want to know about tax cuts they
don't want to know about tax reform
where we're gonna raise your taxes where
we're going to take away your business
is you're going to take away because tax
reform we're going to take away your
farms they don't want the word reform
they want the word tax cuts sir could
you give us a name I'll give you the
name I'll give you the name it's called
the tax cut cut cut cut bill of 27
[Applause]
that's a true story right Steve
that's a such a true sir but even I
thought that was maybe a little bit
hokey with the older cut so we just go
tax cut bill got rid of some of the cuts
they got the word and we got it passed
but would think of it not one Democrat
vote at the heart of our plan is
tremendous relief for working families
and small businesses a typical family of
four earning $75,000 a year will see a
income tax cut of more than $2,000 in
some cases much more than that
slashing their tax bill in half and more
we delivered a historic victory for
American small businesses by allowing
you to deduct twenty percent of your
business income people were shocked
capital investment is soaring on small
businesses and big businesses because
you can now immediately deduct this to
me is the greatest of them all every
single penny spent on new capital
equipment one year bomb deduction
[Applause]
I think that's gonna be the star as you
know we're also bringing back trillions
of dollars from offshore that we
couldn't bring back companies were
unable to do it from a tax standpoint
the amount they had to pay and almost
more importantly was just very hard to
do you had to see the forms that had to
be filled out it was virtually
impossible so we had anywhere from three
trillion to five trillion and now it
seems as though Steve were hitting the
higher side companies are pouring money
back into our country bringing it back
from overseas investing it here Apple
just announced recently they're going to
spend three hundred and fifty billion
dollars on an incredible campus and new
facilities all over the country they're
bringing money back and like nobody ever
thought for sure
and you've heard me say when they said
350 billion I said you mean 350 million
because 350 million builds a nice plant
I know how to build under budget and
ahead of schedule
I can build a beautiful plant for a lot
less than 350 minutes so when I heard
billion I said no no you mean 350
million right they said no think of what
that is I think of the total amount
they're bringing back about two hundred
and thirty billion and the rest they're
putting in tremendous investment in our
country and ExxonMobil is doing the same
thing and so many other countries are
doing the same thing different numbers
it's incredible what's happened
I still say however expensing one year
expensing will be the star of what we're
doing we exempted more small business
owners from the alternative minimum tax
which you know very well was an enormous
waste of your precious time in your very
hard-earned money that was a disasters
tax and from now on most small business
owners will be spared from the deeply
unfair estate tax that I talked about
and it's so I'm so proud of that because
you're all keeping your businesses the
family the farms you're keeping your
businesses as a result of all of these
taxes and all of these tax cuts American
businesses now are in a level playing
field with your competitors from other
countries who have so many advantages
including subsidy by governments you see
what's happening with China we have no
choice this should have been done many
years ago we have no choice China has
been taking out 500 billion dollars a
year out of our country and rebuilding
China I always say we have rebuilt China
they've taken so much it's time folks
it's time so we're gonna get smart and
we're gonna do it right and we're
actually getting a lot of support but we
have to do something about it now maybe
something happens where they come and
they say we agree it's been unfair
for the last 25 years but somehow that
doesn't seem to work so easily but we're
going and we're going to make it fair
we're gonna make it fair with other
countries both our friends and our
enemies and I have to say this in many
cases our friends on trade have treated
as much worse than our enemies pretty
amazing isn't it but we know that when
the rules are fair and you can compete
you will win against anyone anywhere in
the world there's nobody like you you're
gonna win anywhere but you have to bring
it down to a level playing field more
than six million workers
have already received a bonus some Bayou
people or a pay raise or retirement
account contribution or a new job
thanks to these tax cuts a lot of new
jobs and people now are able to go
around and look for jobs they're just
not taking a job and they hate it they
hate to wake up in the morning they
don't want to go to work now they've got
their choice they have jobs that they
could look and they can love and if you
don't love it you're not going to be
good at it
millions of Americans are now saying and
really saying to everybody that they're
saving money on their monthly utility
bills as a result of our business tax
cuts over 100 utility companies have
lowered their prices saving Americans an
additional three billion dollars a year
[Applause]
our historic tax cuts also ended one of
the most unfair taxes imaginable
Obamacare's
individual mandate government will no
longer punish you if you cannot afford
Obamacare sky-high premiums think of
this you pay a lot of money to the
government in order not to have to buy
in health insurance think of it so
you're paying money so that you don't
have to penalty incredibly it was
allowed but you're paying money so that
you don't have to buy health care that
was a beauty it's over it's gone it's
done
and we actually thought we had the votes
and then one man very early in the
morning when thumbs down so that was
that but we almost got rid of Obamacare
without him and that was a very sad day
for the Republican Party that was a very
sad day for the country when that vote
was cast that final vote was cast thumbs
down I remember it well
Obamacare has been especially brutal for
small businesses you know that better
than anybody it caused premiums and
deductibles to explode and healthcare
options to plummet as a result of
Obamacare many small businesses small
business employees sole proprietors have
no good or affordable options but now
they do because we're opening up our
system I'm proud to announce another
truly historic step in our efforts to
rescue Americans from Obamacare and the
Obamacare nightmare and provide high
quality affordable health care to every
American this is low cost great health
care you know before Obamacare there
were many people very happy they had no
problem but then you got thrown to the
wind
Alex Acosta is here stand up Alex this
is so important
Secretary of Labor
Alex and the Department of Labor are
taking a major action that's been worked
on for four months now and now it's
ready to make it easier for small
businesses to band together to negotiate
lower prices for health insurance and
escape some of Obama cares most
burdensome mandates through Association
health plans
[Applause]
you're gonna save massive amounts of
money and have much better health care
it's going to cost you much less it's
going to be I think fantastic and it's
very comprehensive I will tell you a lot
of people big big percentages of this
country are going to be doing that in
fact while you're in the room together
shake hands form an association good
luck and in theory the bigger the
Association the better the deal you're
gonna make you're gonna save a fortune
and you're gonna be able to give
yourselves and your employees tremendous
healthcare I'm really honored by that
belief and that's with this action
businesses in the same state or
businesses in the same industry not just
the same state anywhere in the country
remember I used to say during the
debates cross state lines so you can
negotiate you now can cross state lines
so you can negotiate
[Applause]
so if 20 or 30 of the businesses in this
room get together get together it's a
group an association you pick the
meanest most vicious manage your owner
then the Goethe right right to negotiate
your health care and I know a few of the
people in here that gonna do very well
they are it wild you will end up with
better insurance for far less money you
will end up so great and Alex that's
ready as of when that's not a bad answer
today
[Applause]
I'd call our Secretary of Labor and
they'd say sir he's very busy I said
would have been I'm President of the
United States whatever they said he's
working on health care
I said well Department of Labor that's
interesting and that is some great plan
we love it thank you Alex very committed
to it and he's now working on an
expansion of that including even larger
groups of people so that's really
something that's also going to be very
exciting for the first time ever sole
proprietors will be able to come
together and buy lower cost group
insurance instead of getting ripped off
by this disaster that we all know as
Obamacare these actions will result in
very low prices much more choice much
more freedom including in many cases new
opportunities to purchase health
insurance you'll be able to do this
across state lines that was such a big
thing I'd say Alex I want across state
lines he said don't worry about it and
nobody else you know this is something
we were able to do within the confines
of the existing laws it's a fantastic
thing so it's all set to go get going
make your deals and the insurance
companies and some people are forming
their own but the insurance companies
are so excited about this going to be
very competitive let them go and they've
made so much money off Obamacare folks
they get so rich with Obama take a look
at what happened to a premiums you know
everyone hears about Obamacare being a
disaster except for the insurance
companies so they're gonna have to give
a little bit of that money back
negotiate tough place every American who
owns a small business plays a vital role
in creating a safe strong and prosperous
America and my administration will never
forget that truth every day you turn
ideas into action you turn vision into
creation I know you well and you turn
dreams into reality that's what you do
you don't
realize that's what you do that's what
you do you embody the spirit of
Independence and adventure that turned
America from thirteen colonies into the
most incredible Republic in the history
of humankind see I don't say mankind
anymore I say humankind do the women
understand that I don't know they want
me to be politically correct what look a
couple of women are having the thumb-up
right you like that do you like that
okay that's okay now I'm happy about
it's the same spirit that inspired
previous generations to cross the plains
and tame the wilderness and to build
shining cities that touch the sky we
stand on the shoulders of American
patriots who build the great highways
and railroads who dug out the Panama
Canal who won two world wars and who put
a man on the face of the Moon and if you
see what I did yesterday with NASA right
and you have the Air Force and now you
will soon have the space force because
that's where it's at space that's where
it's at
we'll be the leader together there is
nothing Americans can't do because we
are one people in one family saluting
one great American flag
[Applause]
thank you our future has never looked
brighter and that's because of the
hardworking Americans like you and
millions of small business owners who
took the chance to do what they love to
follow their hearts and to chase their
very beautiful
dreams you are the ones who are shaping
our industry you are the ones who are
shaping and restoring our prosperity we
are restoring our prosperity you've seen
GDP you see what projections are who
knows but numbers that nobody ever
thought possible
I look so forward to seeing some of
those numbers but you see what
projections are people are projecting
numbers like nobody thought even
possible numbers that I would likewise
like I wouldn't have said on jobs I
wouldn't have said on growth I wouldn't
have said let's see what happens but
we're doing well as a country and you're
the ones truly who are making America
great again so happy anniversary god
bless you and God bless the United
States of America thank you very much
[Applause]