FUTURES".
>>> AFTER AN INCREDIBLY BUSY
WEEK IN OUR NATION'S CAPITAL AND
FOR THE COUNTRY, I SAT DOWN FOR
AN INTERVIEW WITH PRESIDENT
EVERYTHING FROM HIS UP COMING
SUPREME COURT PICK TO THE DEBATE
OVER TARIFFS AND PHASE TWO OF
>> MR. PRESIDENT, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH FOR SITTING DOWN WITH ME.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> I WANT TO START WITH THE
BREAKING NEWS OF THE WEEK, AND
THAT IS JUSTICE ANTHONY KENNEDY
ANNOUNCING HIS RETIREMENT.
IS JUSTICE KENNEDY THE MODEL OF
THE PERSON YOU WOULD PUT ON THE
SUPREME COURT NOW?
>> MAYBE SO.
YOU KNOW, I GOT A CALL, MARIA,
ACTING ANONYMOUS.
I SAID WAIT A MINUTE.
I'M THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES.
HOW CAN I SEE SOMEBODY?
WAS A VERY ELEGANT MOMENT.
IT WAS A BEAUTIFUL MOMENT.
HE PRESENTED ME WITH A LETTER,
A VERY -- HE ENDED UP BEING A
LITTLE MORE NEUTRAL THAN A LOT
OF PEOPLE WOULD HAVE PREFERRED,
BUT A LOT OF PEOPLE PREFERRED
THAT HE WAS.
AND WE'RE GOING TO PICK SOMEBODY
WHO IS OUTSTANDING.
I SAID I WILL DO IT IN YOUR
HONOR, BUT WE'RE GOING TO PICK
SOMEBODY WHO IS OUTSTANDING.
I WAS VERY HONORED THAT HE DID
THIS DURING MY TERM.
WHICH MEANS HE HAD CONFIDENCE IN
ME TO DO THE RIGHT THING.
MIGHT VOTE ON ROE VERSUS WADE?
>> WELL, THAT'S A BIG ONE.
AND PROBABLY NOT.
THEY ARE ALL SAYING DON'T DO
THAT.
YOU DON'T DO THAT.
YOU SHOULDN'T DO THAT.
BUT I'M PUTTING CONSERVATIVE
PEOPLE ON.
AND I'M VERY PROUD OF NEIL
HIS OPINIONS ARE, YOU KNOW, SO
WELL WRITTEN, SO BRILLIANT.
AND I'M GOING TO TRY AND DO
SOMETHING LIKE THAT, BUT I DON'T
THINK I'M GOING TO BE SO
SPECIFIC IN THE QUESTIONS I WILL
BE ASKING.
I'M ACTUALLY TOLD THAT I
YOU SAID YOU WOULD LEAVE IT TO
BE TO THE STATES.
YOU NEVER KNOW HOW THAT'S GOING
TO TURN OUT.
THAT'S A VERY COMPLEX QUESTION.
THE ROE V. WADE IS PROBABLY THE
ONE THAT PEOPLE ARE TALKING
ABOUT IN TERMS OF HAVING AN
BUT IT COULD VERY WELL END UP
WITH STATES AT SOME POINT.
>> AND DO YOU THINK YOU WILL BE
ABLE TO GET YOUR NOMINEE IN
PLACE BEFORE THE MIDTERM
ELECTIONS?
>> I THINK IT IS GOING TO VERY
QUICKLY.
I THINK WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A
FROM DEMOCRATS, FRANKLY.
I THINK -- IF IT'S THE RIGHT
PERSON.
I'M GOING TO PICK THE RIGHT
THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
OUTSTANDING, BUT I'M GOING TO
PICK SOMEBODY WHO IS
OUTSTANDING.
YES, I THINK WE WILL GO VERY
QUICKLY.
A LOT OF PEOPLE THINK IT WILL BE
A VERY -- IT IS PROBABLY GOING
TO BE VICIOUS BECAUSE THE OTHER
SIDE ALL THEY CAN DO IS OBSTRUCT
AND RESIST.
YOU KNOW, THE WHOLE THING IS
RESIST.
BUT -- AND MAYBE SOME DAY WE
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT RIGHT NOW IT IS ONLY RESIST.
THAT'S ALL THEY WANT TO DO IS
STOP THINGS FROM HAPPENING.
SO THEY ARE GOING TO TRY VERY
HARD BUT I THINK IT WILL GO
QUICKLY IF I PICK THE RIGHT
INTO LAW A HISTORIC TAX REFORM
PACKAGE.
FIRST TIME IN 30 YEARS.
HAS THE EFFECT BEEN WHAT YOU
EXPECTED?
>> WELL, I THINK THERE'S A
DOUBLE EFFECT.
THE TAX CUTS HAVE BEEN
TAX CUTS HAVE BEEN INCREDIBLE.
>> THE ROLLBACK IN REGULATIONS,
HUGE.
>> I ACTUALLY THINK MAYBE AT
LEAST INITIALLY SPEAKING BECAUSE
IT'S BEEN EARLIER TOOK PLACE
QUICKER, THE REGULATION ROLLBACK
HAS BEEN THE BIGGEST EVER IN THE
HISTORY OF OUR COUNTRY.
NO PRESIDENT EVEN DURING FULL
TERMS HAS CUT BACK ANYWHERE NEAR
WHAT I HAVE DONE.
AND WE HAVE MORE TO DO.
NOW, WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
REGULATION.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE CLEAN WATER.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE, YOU KNOW,
CLEAN AIR.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE THE CLEANEST
WATER, CLEANEST AIR, BUT WE
ARE -- WE HAVE MORE REGULATION
CUTTING TO DO.
I THINK THAT MIGHT HAVE HAD A
BIGGER IMPACT TO THIS POINT.
I THINK ULTIMATELY THE TAX CUTS
AS THEY KICK IN AND THEY ARE
KICKING IN -- YOU SEE THE KIND
OF HUNDREDS OF BILLIONS OF
DOLLARS BROUGHT BACK INTO THE
COUNTRY ALREADY.
I THINK ULTIMATELY THAT'S GOING
TO BE SOMETHING REALLY SPECIAL.
AND YOU'RE SEEING THE RESULT
RIGHT NOW.
>> I AGREE YOU BECAUSE UNDER
OBAMA THE FEDERAL REGISTRY PAGES
WERE UP TO 90,000 SOMETHING
PAGES OR SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
>> IF DEMOCRATS WOULD HAVE WON
THE ELECTION, YOU WOULD HAVE A
LOT OF DIFFERENT -- IF YOU LOOK
AT THE LAST FOUR DECISIONS ON
THE SUPREME COURT AT 5-4, THEY
WOULD HAVE ALL BEEN REVERSED.
THE UNION DECISION WAS A MASSIVE
DECISION.
THE, YOU KNOW, YOU CAN LOOK AT
ANY ONE OF THOSE FOUR, THEY WERE
ALL SO BIG, SO IMPORTANT.
AND THEY WOULD HAVE BEEN EXACTLY
REVERSED.
SO MANY -- THAT'S WHY I'VE
ALWAYS HEARD THAT AS PRESIDENT,
I MEAN OBVIOUSLY OUTSIDE OF WAR
AND PEACE, THE BIGGEST DECISION
YOU CAN MAKE IS THE SELECTION OF
MEAN, THOSE DECISIONS WOULD HAVE
ALL GONE THE OTHER WAY.
>> AND YOUR LEGACY ON THE
CONSERVATIVE PARTY ON THE G.O.P.
IS GOING TO BE MASSIVE OBVIOUSLY
WITH THIS VERY CONSEQUENTIAL
DECISION MAKING THAT YOU NEED TO
DO.
>> RIGHT.
>> LET ME ASK YOU ABOUT WHAT'S
NEXT.
BECAUSE WE'VE SEEN THE IMPACT TO
THE ECONOMY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO SEE HAPPEN
NOW?
DOES THE ECONOMY NEED EVEN MORE
STIMULUS?
ARE YOU LOOKING FOR A PHASE 2 --
>> WE'RE DOING A PHASE 2,
IT WILL BE MORE OF A MIDDLE
CLASS.
WE DID A LOT FOR THE MIDDLE
WE'RE THINKING ABOUT BRINGING
THE 21% DOWN TO 20.
FOR THE MOST PART THE REST OF IT
WOULD GO TO THE MIDDLE CLASS.
IT IS A GREAT STIMULUS.
AND ONE OF THE THINGS I'M DOING
YOU'RE A BELIEVER, BUT I THINK
YOU ARE GETTING THERE, LOOK
WHAT'S HAPPENING WITH THE STEEL
COMPANIES.
THEY ARE EXPANDING.
WE NEED ALUMINIUM.
AND WE NEED SOLAR PANELS.
YOU KNOW, THE SAME THING WITH
SOLAR PANELS, IT WAS LIKE A DEAD
BUSINESS, AND WE DID A 30%
TARIFF BECAUSE THEY WERE DUMPING
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
IS A BIG BUSINESS.
IF YOU LOOK AT WHAT'S HAPPENED
TO STEEL AND ALUMINIUM, WE
PRACTICALLY BUILT A NEW INDUSTRY
IN A PERIOD OF FOUR OR FIVE
MONTHS.
IT IS INCREDIBLE WHAT'S
HAPPENING.
THE BIG THING I'M FOCUSED NOW IS
TRADE.
I HAVE TO STRAIGHTEN OUT TRADE
DEALS.
A DEAL WITH CHINA.
NOBODY BOTHERED TO MAKE A DEAL.
THEY WILL CHARGE 25% FOR A CAR
AND WE CHARGE 2 1/2% AND YOU
HAVE USED THOSE NUMBERS ON YOUR
BUT WE HAVE A -- WE HAVE THE
WORST TRADE DEALS OF THE WORLD.
WE LOSE MONEY WITH EVERYBODY.
YOU KNOW WHEN SOMEBODY ASKS HOW
MUCH DO WE LOSE WITH THIS
COUNTRY?
WE LOSE WITH EVERYBODY.
WE ARE GOING TO MAKE THEM
RECIPROCAL, FAIR, AND I WILL
TELL YOU THAT YOU DON'T KNOW
ABOUT THIS, BUT EVERY COUNTRY IS
IT IS ALL GOING TO WORK OUT
>> I THINK THEY TRUST ME.
THE FARMER TRUST ME.
>> THEY DO.
>> DON'T FORGET, THE FARMERS,
YOU LOOK AT A MAP, IT IS GOT A
LITTLE BLUE ON THE OUTSIDE,
EVERYTHING ELSE IS RED, AND IT'S
BEAUTIFUL COLOR RED, BUT I HAVE
TO SAY THAT IF YOU LOOK AT
DECLINE, OVER THE LAST -- I HAVE
BEEN HERE A YEAR AND A HALF,
OVER THE LAST FIVE YEARS, THEY
HAVE BEEN VERY BAD YEARS FOR
FARMS AND FARMERS.
I SAID WE HAVE TO CHANGE THAT.
AND ONE OF THE REASONS IS
BECAUSE THEY HAVE BARRIERS.
THESE AREN'T EVEN ECONOMIC
BARRIERS.
ALTHOUGH IN CANADA'S CASE, 275%
TARIFF FOR DAIRY.
THAT'S NOT FAIR.
>> WHEN WOULD YOU EXPECT YOUR
MOST SIGNIFICANT DEAL?
>> WELL, I ALREADY PRETTY MUCH
FINISHED THE DEAL WITH SOUTH
KOREA.
IT WAS A TERRIBLE DEAL.
FOR US.
THAT'S DONE.
NAFTA I COULD START IT TOMORROW,
BUT I'M NOT HAPPY WITH IT.
I WANT TO MAKE IT MORE FAIR.
OKAY.
>> I WANT TO WAIT TILL AFTER THE
ELECTION.
YOU ARE GOING TO HAVE AN
IT IS GOING TO BE VERY
INTERESTING.
ARE NOT FINE, I WILL TAX THEIR
CARS COMING INTO AMERICA.
THAT'S THE BIG ONE.
THE CARS ARE THE BIG ONE.
WE COULD TALK STEEL, WE COULD
TALK EVERYTHING.
THE BIG THING IS THE CARS.
>> A MAJOR LOBBYING GROUP FOR
TARIFF ON ALL IMPORTED VEHICLES
WILL AMOUNT TO 45 BILLION
DOLLARS IN TAXES ON CONSUMERS
AND WIPE OUT ANY BENEFITS OF THE
TAX CUT PLAN FOR LOW AND MIDDLE
INCOME AMERICANS.
>> WELL, ACTUALLY IT IS 20%,
TELL THEM TO GET THEIR NUMBERS
RIGHT.
LOOK, MARIA, WHAT'S GOING TO
REALLY HAPPEN THERE'S GOING TO
BE NO TAX.
YOU KNOW WHY?
THEY ARE GOING TO BUILD THEIR
CARS IN AMERICA.
THEY ARE GOING TO MAKE THEM
HERE.
WE BRING IN MILLIONS AND
MILLIONS OF CARS A YEAR.
WE CHARGE 2 1/2%.
SOME OF THESE COUNTRIES DON'T
EVEN TAKE OUR CARS.
IF WE WANT TO SEND GENERAL
MOTORS OR ANY OF OUR COMPANIES
TO SOME OF THESE COUNTRIES, THEY
HAVE A BARRIER, THEY PUT UP A
BARRIER, NONMONETARY BARRIER.
THEY CALL IT NONMONETARY TARIFF.
AND THE BARRIER IS SO STRONG YOU
CAN'T SELL A CAR.
IF YOU DO SELL A CAR, IT IS 10%,
>> YEAH.
DO YOU AGREE THOUGH THAT A
MY SHOW LAST WEEK HE SAID LOOK,
FOR EVERY JOB YOU'RE CREATING IN
THE ALUMINIUM AND STEEL
ALUMINIUM AND STEEL.
THAT'S A SALES TAX.
>> FIRST OF ALL I LOVE FREE
TRADE.
SAID I HAVE AN IDEA EVERYBODY I
WILL GUARANTEE YOU WE WILL DO IT
IMMEDIATELY NOBODY PAY ANYMORE
EVERYBODY ARE YOU ALL SET?
NO MORE TAX.
CANADA
275% FOR YOUR DAIRY AND YOU ARE
GOING TO TAKE DOWN YOUR BARRIERS
K WE WILL TAKE DOWN THE BARRIERS
AND THE TAXES.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED?
EVERYBODY SAID CAN WE GO ON TO
ANOTHER SUBJECT?
BECAUSE AMERICA, OUR COUNTRY
LOST LAST YEAR 817 BILLION
DOLLARS IN TERMS OF DEFICIT.
WE HAD A TRADE DEFICIT, MARIA OF
817 BILLION, WITH A B, DOLLARS
LAST YEAR.
YEARS.
WE HAVE REBUILT CHINA.
I HAVE A GREAT RELATIONSHIP WITH
CHINA.
I HAVE TREMENDOUS RESPECT FOR
HIM, BUT I SAID WE HAVE TO
STRAIGHTEN THIS OUT.
WE CAN'T CONTINUE TO DO THIS.
>> YOU DECIDED TO NOT GO FORWARD
WITH THE INVESTMENT RESTRICTIONS
>> NO, LOOK, 250 BILLION DOLLARS
WORTH OF PRODUCT, THE TARIFFS
ARE -- IN FACT, IT COULD GO UP
TO 500, FRANKLY, IF WE DON'T
I WILL TELL YOU, CHINA WANTS TO
MAKE A DEAL.
IT'S GOT TO BE A FAIR DEAL FOR
THIS COUNTRY.
ONE OF THE HARD THINGS IS, OUR
PRESIDENTS AND OUR BUSINESS
LEADERS, THEY WERE MISSING IN
ACTION.
NOT SO MUCH THE BUSINESS
LEADERS.
YOU KNOW, SOME BUSINESS LEADERS
BENEFIT BY ALLOWING THIS STUFF
TO GO ON, THAT'S THE PROBLEM,
THEY BENEFIT.
THEY'RE MORE FOR THEIR BUSINESS
THAN THEY ARE FOR THE UNITED
STATES.
I HAD THE HEAD OF THE GREAT
COMPANY COME UP TO ME, VERY
SERIOUSLY AFFECTED BY THE
TARIFFS, HE SAID MR. PRESIDENT,
IT IS NOT GOOD FOR ME RIGHT NOW.
ULTIMATELY IT IS, BUT YOU ARE
DOING THE RIGHT THING ON
TARIFFS.
>> YOU ARE DOING THE RIGHT THING
ON PUSHING BACK ON CHINA AS
WELL.
MOST PEOPLE UNDERSTAND THAT THEY
HAVE BEEN STEALING FROM US FOR
>> BUT YOU DIDN'T DO FORWARD
WITH THIS BAN ON CHINESE
NATIONALS ACQUIRING 25% STAKE IN
AMERICAN COMPANIES, NOW PEOPLE
WANT TO KNOW HOW ARE YOU GOING
TO PROTECT AMERICAN INNOVATION,
TECHNOLOGY?
>> WE ARE DOING IT THROUGH
DIFFERENT THINGS WHAT I DIDN'T
LIKE IS PINPOINTING CHINA,
BECAUSE IT'S NOT FAIR.
I GET SAY LONG WITH CHINA.
I LIKE THE PRESIDENT.
PRESIDENT FOR LIFE, WE CAN CALL
HIM THE KING; RIGHT?
I LIKE THE PRESIDENT.
I DIDN'T LIKE PINPOINTING CHINA.
I DON'T THINK IT'S FAIR.
THEY ARE NOT THE ONLY ONE.
NOW THEY ARE BIGGER AND STRONGER
AND FRANKLY THEY DO IT MORE AND
THEY'RE PROBABLY A BIGGER
VIOLATOR, BUT IT IS OTHER
COUNTRIES TOO.
I WANTED TO GO WORLDWIDE.
AND WE'RE DOING THAT.
SO ACTUALLY WHAT I'M DOING IS A
VERY SIMILAR THING, BUT I WANT
IT TO PERTAIN TO EVERYBODY.
SO YOU MEAN CHINA CAN'T DO IT
BUT OTHER COUNTRIES CAN?
I KNOW CHINA AND I KNOW HOW
SMART THEY ARE.
THEY WILL SEND THEIR PEOPLE INTO
THROUGH OTHER COUNTRIES AND GO
THROUGH AN EXTRA PROCESS
>> THAT'S WHY YOU HAD TO DO IT
TO EVERYBODY, EVEN OUR FRIENDS?
>> I WANT EVERYBODY TO DO IT.
SAME THING WITH THE TARIFFS ON
THE STEEL, IF WE DON'T HAVE IT
AMERICAN TECHNOLOGY AND
INNOVATION.
MORE NOW ON MY EXCLUSIVE
INTERVIEW.
MARIA: IF WE'RE TRYING TO STOP
CHINA FROM STEALING FROM US,
WHICH WE KNOW IS HAPPENING.
>> IT IS TRUE.
MARIA: EXACTLY.
WOULD IT BE BETTER TO ACTUALLY
HAVE OUR ALLIES TOGETHER TO GO
AGAINST CHINA INSTEAD OF PUSHING
BACK ON OUR ALLIES LIKE EUROPEAN
NATIONS?
>> TH
>> THE
>> THE E
>> THE EUR
>> THE EUROP
>> THE EUROPEA
>> THE EUROPEAN
>> THE EUROPEAN UN
>> THE EUROPEAN UNIO
>> THE EUROPEAN UNION,
>> THE EUROPEAN UNION, T
LOOK AT THE CAR SITUATION, THEY
SEND A MERCEDES IN, WE CAN'T
SEND OUR CARS IN.
LOOK WHAT THEY DO TO OUR
FARMERS.
THEY DON'T WANT OUR FARM
PRODUCTS.
THEY HAVE THEIR FARMERS THEY
WANT TO PROTECT THEIR FARMERS.
WE DON'T PROTECT OURS AND THEY
LOOK AT A TRADE SURPLUS WHICH I
THINK IS A VERY IMPORTANT THING,
MANY YEARS AGO MEANING MY
PARENTS WERE BORN IN THE
EUROPEAN UNION.
I LOVE THOSE COUNTRIES.
GERMANY AND ALL OF THE COUNT
RIS.
SCOTLAND.
-- GERMANY AND ALL OF THE
COUNTRIES, SCOTLAND.
THEY TREAT US VERY BADLY.
EXCUSE ME, I CAN SAY IT IN A
DIFFERENT WAY.
THEY MADE LAST YEAR 151 BILLION
DOLLARS IN TRADE SURPLUS.
MARIA: ON AMERICA.
>> WE HAD A DEFICIT WITH THE EU
COMING MIDTERM ELECTIONS AND HOW
SOME DEMOCRATS IN THEIR CALL TO
ABOLISH I.C.E. COULD ULTIMATELY
YESTERDAY, AND YOU CALLED OUT
HARLEY-DAVIDSON AND YOU HAVE
BEEN CALLING OUT --
>> I DON'T LIKE THAT THEY ARE
LEAVING.
THEY ARE NOT LEAVING --
BECAUSE WE CAN'T DEAL WITH THE
RETALIATORY TARIFFS OUT OF
EUROPE THAT'S BECAUSE OF OUR
TARIFFS.
SHOULD YOU BE CALLING OUT
SPECIFIC COMPANIES?
YOU ARE THE PRESIDENT.
>> YES I SHOULD.
I DEVOTED A LOT OF TIME TO
HARLEY-DAVIDSON VOTED FOR TRUMP.
THEY CALLED BIKERS FOR TRUMP.
NOW, WE JUST PROPOSED THIS A FEW
DAYS AGO.
THEY MADE THIS DEAL AT THE
BEGINNING OF THE YEAR, LONG
BEFORE THEY EVER HEARD OF THE
WORD TARIFF.
THEY MADE THIS DEAL AT THE
IT.
I THINK THAT HARLEY IS AN
AMERICAN BIKE.
IT IS AN AMERICAN MOTORCYCLE.
AND THEY SHOULD BUILD THEM IN
THIS COUNTRY.
THEY SHOULDN'T PLAY CUTE.
MONTHS AGO.
MARIA: I REMEMBER.
>> THEY WERE TELLING ME IN INDIA
THEY CHARGE 100%.
MARIA: YOU SAID THAT.
>> I THINK I TAUGHT THEM MORE
ABOUT TARIFFS THAN I COULD EVER
LEARN.
100%.
I GOT THEM TO REDUCE THE TARIFFS
IN INDIA BECAUSE THEY USED THAT
AS AN EXAMPLE.
ALL OF A SUDDEN HARLEY LEAVES.
EVERYONE ELSE IS COMING IN.
THEY ARE ONE OF THE FEW.
HARLEY -- I THINK THEY ARE GOING
TO TAKE A BIG HIT.
I THINK IT IS A GREAT AMERICAN
PRODUCT, AND OUR PEOPLE HAVE
MORE PRIDE THAN THEY USED TO
HAVE.
I REALLY BELIEVE THAT HARLEY'S
GOING TO TAKE -- THE PEOPLE THAT
ARE BUYING HARLEY-DAVIDSON, THEY
DON'T WANT IT BUILT IN ANOTHER
COUNTRY.
MARIA: THAT'S TRUE.
>> I KNOW THOSE PEOPLE.
THEY ARE MY VOTERS.
MARIA: THEY HAVE PRIDE THAT
>> THOSE ARE MY VOTERS THEY
DON'T WANT HARLEY-DAVIDSON
GETTING CUTE TO MAKE $2 MORE.
IMMIGRATION.
IS IMMIGRATION AND SEPARATION OF
FAMILIES GOING TO HURT THE
I SIGNED AN EXECUTIVE ORDER THAT
I DON'T WANT FAMILIES BREAK UP.
>> OUR FIRST LADY --
>> SHE'S BEEN THERE AND OUT TO
THE BORDER TWICE.
>> SHE CAME HOME AND TOLD ME IT
IS A VERY SAD SITUATION, VERY
VERY SAD.
SHE WAS REALLY IMPRESSED WITH
THE PLIGHT OF PEOPLE, I MEAN,
YOU KNOW, SHE HAS A VERY BIG
WEEK AND A HALF.
SHE FEELS IT.
BUT SHE WAS SO STRONG ON HOW
PROFESSIONAL THE BORDER PATROL,
SHE SAW THE DANGER.
IT JUST LOOKS LIKE DANGER.
IN THE MEANTIME, WE HAVE TO HAVE
STRONG BORDER PROTECTION.
WE HAVE TO HAVE STRONG BORDERS.
BORDERS.
THEY WANT TO GET RID OF I.C.E.
MARIA: I WAS GOING TO SAY THAT.
AND GET THIS MORE DEMOCRATS ARE
GETTING IN LINE WITH THAT.
GILLIBRAND SAYING WE NEED TO
ABOLISH I.C.E.
>> I HOPE THEY KEEP THINKING OF
THAT.
THEY ARE GOING TO GET BEATEN SO
BADLY.
THESE ARE THE GUYS THAT GO IN
AND TAKE MS 13 AND THEY TAKE
THEM OUT BECAUSE THEY ARE MUCH
OF YOUR HOUSE.
YOU ARE GOING TO HAVE A COUNTRY
THAT'S CRIME RIDDEN, THE BORDER
PATROL, THE BORDER PATROL
AGENTS, I.C.E., THESE PEOPLE ARE
INCREDIBLE, THEY WERE THE ONES
ACTUALLY WHEN MELANIA WENT DOWN,
SHE WAS TALKING ABOUT THE BORDER
ARE INCREDIBLE PATRIOTS.
YOU KNOW LONG ISLAND VERY WELL.
MARIA: CATCH AND RELEASE.
IF THEY DO THAT, LIKE I ALWAYS
YOU HAVE OPEN BORDERS, ALL IT'S
GOING TO DO IS LEAD TO MASSIVE,
MASSIVE CRIME.
THAT'S GOING TO BE THEIR
PLATFORM.
OPEN BORDERS WHICH EQUALS CRIME.
PRESIDENT CAN BRING THE COUNTRY
TOGETHER AS THE POLITICAL
RHETORIC GROWS MORE EXTREME.
TAKE A LOOK.
REAL QUICK ON NORTH KOREA AND
IRAN, HOW WAS THE SUMMIT?
CAN YOU GIVE US ANECDOTES?
WE ARE SUPPOSED TO FIND OUT -- I
HAVE SPOKEN WITH SOME MILITARY
OF MY OWN AND THEY TOLD ME THAT
NORTH KOREA NEEDS TO TELL US
EXACTLY WHERE THEIR FACILITIES
ARE SO WE CAN INSPECT THEM
WITHIN THE NEXT FEW WEEKS.
IF WE DON'T FIND OUT IN THE NEXT
FEW WEEKS, WE KNOW THEY ARE NOT
SERIOUS ABOUT THIS.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
>> I THINK THEY ARE VERY SERIOUS
ABOUT IT.
WE HAD A VERY GOOD CHEMISTRY.
YOU KNOW, WE HAD A LOT OF
POINTS.
WE WENT ON A LOT OF DIFFERENT
POINTS, NOT TO GO OVER THEM,
DENUCLEARIZATION GETTING THE
REMAINS BACK FROM GREAT HEROES,
GREAT PEOPLE, GETTING THE
HOSTAGES BACK.
MARIA: THAT WAS INCREDIBLE.
THANK YOU FOR DOING THAT, MR.
PRESIDENT.
>> WHAT DID I DO, REALLY, WHEN
YOU THINK OF IT?
I WENT THERE.
SO WE HAD A MEETING.
WE DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
NOW, I ASKED, I SAID LET'S NOT
DO -- I CALL THEM THE WAR GAMES,
THEY ARE DROPPING BOMBS ALL OVER
THE PLACE EVERY SIX MONTHS.
IT IS UNBELIEVABLY EXPENSIVE TO
DO THAT.
PLANES FLY IN FROM GUAM, THESE
MASSIVE, YOU KNOW, BOMBERS, AND
THEY ARE FLYING IN FROM GUAM, IT
IS CRAZY.
SO WE GAVE NOTHING.
WHAT WE ARE GOING TO GIVE IS
NORTH KOREA HAS A TREMENDOUS
FUTURE.
I GOT A LONG REALLY -- I GOT
ALONG REALLY WELL WITH CHAIRMAN
KIM.
WE HAD A GREAT CHEMISTRY.
WE REALLY HAD -- CHAIRMAN --
MARIA: DO WE BELIEVE HIM, MR.
PRESIDENT?
>> I'VE MADE A DEAL WITH HIM.
I SHOOK HANDS WITH HIM.
I REALLY BELIEVE HE MEANS IT.
NOW, IS IT POSSIBLE -- HAVE I
BEEN IN DEALS?
ON IRAN.
I MEAN, THIS WAS INCREDIBLE.
>> IRAN LOOK WHAT'S HAPPENING IN
PROTESTS PEOPLE WANT ECONOMIC
FREEDOM.
>> IRAN'S A DIFFERENT PLACE.
THEY ARE NO LONGER THINKING
ABOUT THE MEDITERRANEAN AND
GOING THROUGH -- THEY ARE
THINKING ABOUT THEMSELVES.
THEY ARE HAVING RIOTS.
>> ARE THEY ENRICHING ROOUR
>> ARE THEY ENRICH INGROOU
>> ARE THEY ENRICH IN
>> ARE THEY ENRICHINN
>> ARE THEY ENRICHING
>> ARE THEY ENRICHIN
>> ARE THEY ENRICH I
>> ARE THEY ENRICH ING
>> ARE THEY ENRICH IN
>> ARE THEY ENRICHINN
>> ARE THEY ENRICHING
>> ARE THEY ENRICHING U
>> ARE THEY ENRICHING URA
>> ARE THEY ENRICHING URANI
>> ARE THEY ENRICHING URANIUM
LIKE THE REPORTS SAY?
>> IF THEY DO, THEY ARE GOING TO
>> 100%, OPEC IS AND THEY BETTER
STOP IT.
WE'RE PROTECTING MANY OF THOSE
COUNTRIES.
OPEC IS MANIPULATING.
THEY HAVE TO PUT OUT ANOTHER 2
MILLION BARRELS IN MY OPINION
BECAUSE WE DON'T WANT THAT
HAPPENING.
DON'T FORGET THE ONE NEGATIVE TO
THE IRAN DEAL IS YOU'RE GOING TO
LOSE A LOT OF OIL.
AND THEY'RE GOING TO MAKE UP FOR
IT.
WHO IS THEIR BIG ENEMY?
IRAN.
YOU THINK OF IT.
THEY WILL HAVE TO DO IT.
I HAVE A VERY GOOD RELATIONSHIP
WITH THE KING AND WITH THE CROWN
PRINCE OF SAUDI ARABIA AND THE
OTHERS AROUND, AND THEY ARE
GOING TO PUT OUT MORE OIL.
>> ANY COMMENTS ON PETER STRZOK
AND THESE TESTIMONIES THAT WE'RE
SEEING, ROSENSTEIN, CHRISTOPHER
WRAY, WHY DON'T YOU JUST DIRECT
YOUR SUBORDINATES TO GET THOSE
DOCUMENTS OVER TO CONGRESS?
ARE YOU GOING TO DO IT?
>> SO I HAVE THIS COUNTRY
RUNNING AT THE TOP, MIKE POMPEO
IS DOING GREAT.
WE HAVE A GREAT GROUP OF PEOPLE.
THE ONE THING I WANT TO STAY
UNINVOLVED IN AT LEAST FOR NOW I
MAY GET INVOLVED BUT I HAVE BEEN
TOLD BY SO MANY PEOPLE DON'T GET
INVOLVED.
IT'S NOT GOOD.
THEY WILL GET THE DOCUMENTS.
THEY ARE GREAT PEOPLE.
I DIDN'T LIKE THE SCENE THE
OTHER DAY WHERE EVERYBODY IS
SCREAMING AT EACH OTHER.
I DON'T LIKE THAT.
IT IS BAD FOR THE COUNTRY.
IF RUSSIA IS IN FACT LOOKING TO
SOW DISCORD OR CHAOS, THEY HAVE
GOT TO BE SAYING THIS IS THE
GREATEST THING WE HAVE EVER
DONE.
OKAY?
NOW, THERE'S NO COLLUSION WITH
ME.
THERE'S NO RUSSIA WITH ME.
THERE'S NO NOTHING.
BUT I PURPOSELY SAID I'M NOT
GETTING INVOLVED.
LET IT JUST GO.
YOU KNOW, THEY FOUND NOTHING.
NOBODY HAS FOUND ANYTHING.
MARIA: I KNOW.
ARE YOU GOING --
>> BY THE WAY, THIS IS THE MOST
TRANSPARENT THING EVER DONE WITH
THE WHITE HOUSE.
I THINK I GAVE THEM A MILLION
400,000 DOCUMENTS I TOLD THEM
DON'T EVEN READ THEM.
THERE'S NO RUSSIA MENTIONED OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
THEY HAVE NOTHING.
IT IS TERRIBLE.
IT IS BAD FOR BOTH SIDES.
MARIA: ARE YOU GOING TO MENTION
THE MEDDLING WHEN YOU MEET WITH
THE RUSSIAN PRESIDENT?
>> I WOULD LIKE TO SEE SOME
TAKE THE SERVER FROM THE DNC.
>> THE DNC WANTED TO GIVE IT TO
A PRIVATE COMPANY.
THEY DIDN'T WANT TO GIVE IT TO
THE FBI.
>> WHY DIDN'T THE FBI TAKE IT?
LOOK WHAT THEY DID TO OTHER
PEOPLE.
WHY DIDN'T THEY TAKE IT?
HOW CAN THE DNC SAY GET OUT OF
HERE.
THEY THREW THEM OUT OF THE
OFFICE.
>> THE SAME PEOPLE RUNNING BOTH
INVESTIGATIONS.
THAT'S WHY.
>> DID YOU EVER SEE A DIFFERENCE
IN TWO INVESTIGATIONS?
>> HUGE DIFFERENCE, MR.
PRESIDENT.
>> THE DIFFERENCE HERE THIS ONE
DID NOTHING WRONG, NO COLLUSION,
NO NOTHING.
THE OTHER ONE -- I'M NOT SAYING
ONE WAY OR THE OTHER, BUT YOU GO
BACK, HOW ABOUT THE E-MAILS
DELETING 33,000 E-MAILS?
WE DON'T EVEN HAVE TO TALK ABOUT
THE URANIUM AND ALL THE
DIFFERENT -- JUST TELL ME, YOU
GET A SUBPOENA.
AND AFTER GETTING THE SUBPOENA
FROM THE UNITED STATES CONGRESS,
RIGHT?
PEOPLE GO TO JAIL FOR DOING IT
ON A CIVIL CASE.
THEY DELETE 33,000 E-MAILS.
MARIA: SOME OF THEM GOT
IMMUNITY.
>> BEFORE THE FBI EVEN WALKED
IN, THEY ARE WALKING IN AND SAY
YOU HAVE -- BY THE WAY, KEEP
YOUR LAPTOPS AND THEN THEY EVEN
SAY DESTROY YOUR LAPTOPS OR
DESTROY YOUR LAPTOPS?
WE SEE PETER FONDA ROBERT DE
VITRIOL IN THIS COUNTRY, AS THE
COMMANDER-IN-CHIEF, AS THE
PRESIDENT OF THIS GREAT COUNTRY,
WHAT CAN YOU DO TO BRING US
TOGETHER?
>> SOME OF THEM DO IT FOR
PUBLICITY.
I HATE TO SAY IT.
SOME OF THEM DO IT FOR
PUBLICITY.
THE RESTAURANT I THOUGHT IT WAS
TERRIBLE WITH SARAH.
>> IT IS ALL TERRIBLE.
>> I THINK SOME OF THE THINGS
THAT ARE SAID ARE TERRIBLE.
AND YOU KNOW, IT'S OUR PEOPLE
ARE SO INCREDIBLE -- DO YOU
KNOW, THERE'S PROBABLY NEVER
BEEN A BASE IN THE HISTORY OF
POLITICS IN THIS COUNTRY LIKE MY
BASE.
I HOPE THE OTHER SIDE REALIZES
THEY BETTER JUST TAKE IT EASY
BECAUSE SOME OF THE LANGUAGE
USED, SOME OF THE WORDS USED,
I THINK THEY ARE ACTUALLY VERY
DANGEROUS FOR THE COUNTRY.
>> ALL THE WHILE YOU ARE
CREATING ECONOMIC GROWTH AND JOB
OPPORTUNITIES.
>> SO IF YOU LOOK AT BLACK
UNEMPLOYMENT, THE BEST IN
HISTORY.
HISPANIC UNEMPLOYMENT, THE BEST
IN HISTORY.
LOWEST IN THE HISTORY OF OUR
65 YEARS, WITHIN TWO WEEKS IT
SHOULD BE THE BEST IN HISTORY,
SO LOW.
SO BEAUTIFUL.
OUR UNEMPLOYMENT PICTURE OVERALL
GENERALLY IS ALMOST THE BEST IN
HISTORY.
OUR NUMBERS ARE AMONG -- IT IS
GOING TO BE INTERESTING TO SEE
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE NEXT
QUARTER.
BUT, YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW IF
YOU SAW IT, BUT THE ATLANTA FED
PREDICTED 4.8.
I DON'T KNOW --
MARIA: OF COURSE I SAW.
>> I SAW IT ON YOUR SHOW.
MARIA: THANK YOU.
>> MAYBE YOU WEREN'T WATCHING.
MARIA: I WAS ON THE SHOW.
[LAUGHTER]
>> BUT THE ATLANTA FED PREDICTED
4.6.
THEN THEY UPPED IT TO 4.8.
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT'S TRUE.
BUT EACH POINT IS 3 TRILLION
DOLLARS AND 10 MILLION JOBS.
AND YOU KNOW THAT WHEN I
ORIGINALLY TOOK OVER, IT WAS
THEY WANTED TO PUT MORE -- WE
TALKED ABOUT THE REGULATIONS AND
RESTRICTIONS.
THEY WANTED TO PUT MORE
REGULATIONS ON.
THEY WOULDN'T HAVE DONE ANY TAX
CUTS.
FOR THE TAX CUTS WE DIDN'T GET
ONE DEMOCRAT VOTE.
NOW, ADD THIS TO IT, PART OF
THEIR PLATFORM, ONE OTHER THING
THEY WANT TO DO, THEY WANT TO
RAISE THE TAXES.
WANT TO RAISE THE TAXES.
I DON'T THINK THAT'S A VERY GOOD
FORMULA FOR THE COUNTRY, NUMBER
ONE, MOST IMPORTANTLY BUT ALSO
NOT A GOOD FORMULA TO GET
ELECTED.
MARIA: YOU THINK THIS WILL BE
THE KEY THAT WILL DRIVE VOTERS
IN THE NOVEMBER ELECTION?
>> I THINK THE TAX CUTS WILL BE
IMPORTANT.
I THINK THE REGULATIONS WILL BE
>> HONESTLY I FEEL ACTUALLY
GOOD.
THE ONLY THING I FEEL BAD ABOUT
IS THAT I GUESS 93% OF THE TIME
WHOEVER WINS THE PRESIDENCY
TENDS TO DO NOT SO GOOD IN THE
MAY BE -- LOOK YOU DO THIS FOR A
LIVING AND NOBODY DOES IT
BETTER, THIS MAY BE THE GREATEST
ECONOMY WE HAVE EVER HAD.
SO IF IT'S ALL ABOUT THE
ECONOMY, I THINK WE SHOULD DO
PHENOMENALLY.
I THINK WE'RE GOING TO DO GREAT
IN THE SENATE.
I VISITED THREE STATES IN THE
LAST SIX DAYS.
I THINK EVERY ONE OF THOSE
PEOPLE HAVE AN AWFULLY GOOD
IN THE SENATE.
I THINK WE'RE GOING TO GO
BACK TO THE CAMPAIGN RALLY.
>> I DO LIKE IT.
COUNTRY.
THEY ARE GREAT.
MARIA: I SEE IT.
>> THANK YOU MARIA.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR
JOINING US.
>> THANK YOU.
TRUMP FOR JOINING US.
YOU HEARD THE PRESIDENT MENTION
OIL PRICES YESTERDAY HE TWEETED
IRAN AND VENEZUELA I'M ASKING
THAT SAUDI ARABIA INCREASE OIL
DIFFERENCE.
PRICES TO HIGH.
HE HAS AGREED.
-- PRICES TOO HIGH.
THE WHITE HOUSE ISSUED A
STATEMENT SAYING THE SAUDI KING
AGREED TO RAISE OUTPUT IF NEEDED